Guide to Barbara Sloan European Union Document Collection, 1951-2004 EUDC
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Barbara Sloan European Union Document Collection
1951-2004
ULS Archives & Special Collections
European Commission. Delegation (U.S.)
EUDC
650 Linear Feet
This collection is essentially a "government documents" collection for both the organization currently known as the European Union and for its precursors: European Coal and Steel Community; European Atomic Energy Community; European Economic Community; European Communities. This is an extensive collection of publications and documentation which these organizations intended to make publicly available. The collection does not include any personal papers of individuals.
Access Restrictions
Materials do not circulate and are available by appointment. Contact person: Dan Pennell (pennell@pitt.edu)
Arrangement
All materials are arranged into three broad categories:
Series I. EUROPEAN COMMUNITY General. This includes material on the institutions which have comprised the Community – European Coal and Steel Community (ECSC), European Community (EC), European Atomic Energy Community (Euratom), European Economic Community (EEC),and European Union (EU) – and subjects which are not Policy Areas.
Series II. POLICY AREA topics relate mostly to the activities of Commission Directorate-Generals, such as Agriculture, Energy, etc.
Series III. MISCELLANEOUS includes all items which do not fit in the first two categories. Most of these deal very little with, but have some relevance for, EU affairs.
Related Material
For more information on the EUDC and the AEI, please see:
University Library System Expands Access to Resources on the EU Through Digitization.
Electronic Access to Documents and Publications on the European Union: The Role of the Archive of European Integration.
European Union Archival Collection at the University of Pittsburgh. Pages 32-41
European Information: a guide to official sources. 4th ed. 2010.
History
This collection was compiled by personnel working in the Delegation Library during the period early 1950s-2004. It contains two main categories of publications. The first is monograph and serial publications, ranging from a few to hundreds of pages in length, which are usually classed and put on shelves in libraries. This category consists of about 1750 linear shelf feet, housed in closed shelves. This collection is shelved according to a letter and number system based on policy area.
The second category is best described as working or internal documents, primarily from the Commission. These cover the entire range of activities of the Community and its institutions. These are usually short, stapled documents which would not be individually classed by libraries and placed on shelves. Most of this category of documents are housed in the "research files" section of the EUDC, organized by subject and stored in folders housed in cabinets. Materials are in chronological order within folders. The "research file" collection is filed under a numerical classification system derived from the Universal Decimal Classification system.
NOTE: this finding aid describes ONLY this second category of documents (the "research files") and not the shelf collection.
Scope and Content Notes
The collection of "research files" contains legislative histories for all Community policies. Documents includes proposals from the Commission in the form of COM and SEC documents, Parliament session documents, Economic and Social Committee opinions, common opinions of the Council and the texts of final legislation. Also included are the press releases of the institutions, written questions of the Parliament with replies, along with working documents of the Commission. The legislative documents are supplemented with articles from European and American newspapers, Agence Europe (published by a company with same name in Luxembourg and Brussels), and European Report (published by Europe Information Service, Brussels). There are also a limited number of journal articles not published by the European Community.
European Union countries -- Economic conditions; European Union countries -- Politics and government; European Union countries; European Union countries -- Economic policy; European Union; European Union Documentation Center (U.S.); European Commission
- EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES General, I.
  - ATLANTIC AFFAIRS, 1.
    - Atlantic Affairs [490 A], 1962-1995; 1.; 1 folder 6" (Box 377)
    - Atlantic Affairs; Atlantic Council of the US [490 B], 1966-1977; 2.; 1 folder 1" (Box 377)
    - Atlantic Affairs; Atlantic Institute [490 C], 1963-2000; 3.; 1 folder 2" (Box 377)
    - NATO [488.8], 1959-2003; 4.; 2 folders 7" (Box 376)
    - East West Relations; Including Commission on Security and Cooperation in Europe (CSCE) [491], 1970-1999; 5.; 2 folders 10" (Box 377)
    - Technology in the Atlantic Area [62.001.5(8)], 1960-2002; 6.; 1 folder 3" (Box 390)
    - Scientific Research in the Atlantic Area [5.001.5(8)], 1968-1971; 7.; 1 folder 0.5" (Box 378)
    - NAFTA (North Atlantic Free Trade Area) [337.1(51)(102)(103)], 1966-1991; 8.; 2 folders 1" (Box 12)
    - International Trade Atlantic (Europe-America) [382(8)], 1966-1992; 9.; 1 folder 0.5" (Box 30)
  - COMMUNITY LAW & CONVENTIONS, 2.
    - Recognition & Execution of Foreign Judicial Decisions - General [341.518], 1964-2003; 1.; 2 folders 6" (Box 20)
    - Obligations Civil Laws & Conventions [347.4], 1979-2003; 2.; 1 folder 2" (Box 23)
    - Bankruptcy [347.736], 1973-2002; 3.; 1 folder 3" (Box 23)
    - Law, European Community [421], 1961-2003; 4.; 1 folder 4" (Box 56)
    - Law, Community & Member State Laws [421: 34(25)], 1960-2003; 5.; 1 folder 3" (Box 56)
  - EUROPEAN ATOMIC ENERGY COMMUNITY, 3.
    - EUROPEAN ATOMIC ENERGY COMMUNITY General
      - EUROPEAN ATOMIC ENERGY COMMUNITY General [46], 1957-1992; 1.; 1 folder 4" (Box 373)
      - Treaty & Legal Questions, Euratom [461], 1966-1999; 2.; 1 folder 1" (Box 373)
      - Commission, Euratom [462], 1960; 3.; 1 folder 0.5" (Box 373)
      - Budget & Financial Questions, Euratom [462.11], 1961-1993; 4.; 1 folder 1" (Box 374)
      - Personnel Staff Regulations (Including Remunerations) [432.122], 1968-2003; 5.; 2 folders 8" (Box 80)
    - NUCLEAR ENERGY
      - Nuclear Common Market, Euratom [466.17], 1976; 1.; 1 folder 0.5" (Box 374)
      - Nuclear Energy & Electricity, General [4417.5], 1970-1993; 2.; 1 folder 1" (Box 362)
      - Nuclear Energy [4417.51], 1967-2003; 3.; 2 folders 4"
    - NUCLEAR RESEARCH
      - EURATOM Situation [4412.2], 1966-2002; 1.; 1 folder 2" (Box 307)
      - Nuclear Research Programs [4412.21], 2.; 1 folder (Box 307)
      - Research, Nuclear Power Plants [4412.221], 1958-2003; 3.; 1 folder 5" (Box 309)
      - Fusion Program; Joint European Torus [4412.212], 1970-2002; 4.; 2 folder 6" (Box 309)
      - Nuclear Industry, Joint Enterprises [4412.213], 1961-2002; 5.; 1 folder 2" (Box 309)
    - JOINT NUCLEAR RESEARCH CENTER General
      - JOINT NUCLEAR RESEARCH CENTER General [4415], 1968-2002; 1.; 2 folders 9" (Box 349)
      - Joint Research Center, Geel [4415.4], 1970-1980; 2.; 1 folder 0.5" (Box 350)
      - Joint Research Center, Ispra [4415.1], 1959-1996; 3.; 1 folder 1" (Box 349)
      - Joint Research Center, Karlsruhe [4415.3], 1960-1988; 4.; 1 folder 1" (Box 350)
      - Joint Research Center, Petten [4415.2], 1961-2002; 5.; 1 folder 1" (Box 349)
    - EURATOM SUPPLY AGENCY
      - EURATOM SUPPLY AGENCY [4421], 1970-2003; 1.; 3 folders 9" (Box 366)
      - Nuclear Fuel Supplies [4421], 1970-2003; 2.; 3 folders 9" (Box 366)
      - Uranium Enrichment, Standing Committee on [4421.1], 1973-1980; 3.; 1 folder 0.5" (Box 366)
      - Nuclear Fuel Cycle Evaluation, International [4421.2], 1977-1990; 4.; 1 folder 1" (Box 367)
    - NUCLEAR FUEL CONTROLS AND SAFEGUARDS
      - NUCLEAR FUEL CONTROLS AND SAFEGUARDS [4422], 1958-2002; 1.; 2 folders 9" (Box 367)
    - NUCLEAR HEALTH AND SAFETY MEASURES
      - Health Protection (Nuclear Contamination) [445.7], 1960-1993; 1.; 1 folder 2" (Box 223)
      - Nuclear Hygiene & Medicine [445.71], 1966-2003; 2.; 1 folder 1" (Box 223)
      - Radioactive Waste & Nuclear Safety Measures [445.72], 1970-2003; 3.; 3 folders 13" (Box 223)
      - Basic Standards - Euratom [445.73], 1959-2002; 4.; 1 folder 4" (Box 224)
      - Radiobiology [621.039: 57], 1964-1983; 5.; 1 folder 1" (Box 390)
      - Nuclear Hygiene & Medicine (Including Atomic Energy in Agriculture) [621.039: 61], 1968-1991; 6.; 1 folder 0.5" (Box 390)
      - Radioactive Wastes; Radioactive Contamination [621.039.7], 1969-2001; 7.; 1 folder 1" (Box 390)
    - NUCLEAR INSURANCE
      - Nuclear Insurance & 3rd Party Liability [621.039: 368.86], 1958-2003; 1.; 1 folder 2" (Box 390)
    - INDUSTRIAL APPLICATONS OF NUCLEAR ENERGY
      - Reactor Development, Euratom [621.039.572], 1.; 1 folder 1" (Box 390)
      - Thermonuclear Reactions, Euratom [539.1], 2. (Box 379)
      - Nuclear Power Plants [621.039.577], 1961-1997; 3.; 1 folder 1" (Box 390)
      - Nuclear Ship Propulsion [621.039.578: 6(CST 735)], 1959-1971; 4.; 1 folder 2" (Box 390)
      - Bureau EURISOTOP; Measures to Improve Existing and Introduce New Techniques in Industry [443.34], 1965-1984; 5.; 1 folder 2" (Box 195)
    - DISSEMINATION OF INFORMATION General
      - DISSEMINATION OF INFORMATION General [4413], 1960-1997; 1.; 1 folder 1" (Box 310)
      - Industrial Property, Patents, Dissemination of Research Results [4413.1], 1966-2000; 2.; 1 folder 1" (Box 312)
      - Committee for Information & Documentation on Science and Technology [4413.31], 1973-1991; 3.; 1 folder 1" (Box 312)
      - European Computer Program Library [4413.32], 1972-1991; 4.; 1 folder 1" (Box 312)
      - Information & Documentation Center (CID) [4413.2], 1964-1984; 5.; 1 folder 1" (Box 312)
      - Research, Instruction Training Basic Research [4412.4], 1971-2003; 6.; 1 folder 1" (Box 312)
    - EXTERNAL RELATIONS
      - Scientific Technical & Nuclear Affairs, International Aspects after 7/1/68 [441.4], 1959-2003; 1.; 2 folders 5" (Box 165)
      - External Relations, Euratom (Before 7/1/68) [466.8], 1958-1966; 2.; 1 folder 2" (Box 374)
      - Multilateral Relations, Euratom (Before 7/1/68 ) [466.83], 1960 and 1966; 3.; 1 folder 0.5" (Box 374)
      - International Atomic Energy Agency [469.2], 1959-2003; 4.; 1 folder 2" (Box 374)
  - EUROPEAN & OTHER INTERNATIONAL ORGANIZATIONS, 4.
    - Bank for International Settlements [332.155.1], 1965-1986; 1.; 1 folder 1" (Box 9)
    - Belgium, Luxembourg, Netherlands (BENELUX) [488.2], 1972-1996; 2.; 1 folder 1" (Box 375)
    - Benelux Plan European Integration [420.42], 1968; 3.; 1 folder 1" (Box 53)
    - Council for Mutual Economic Assistance (COMECON) [488.5], 1963-1990; 4.; 1 folder 2" (Box 375)
    - Council of Europe [481], 1960-2003; 5.; 1 folder 3" (Box 375)
    - Customs Co-operation Council [488.6], 1973-1990; 6.; 1 folder 1" (Box 375)
    - European Free Trade Association (EFTA) [473], 1959-1992; 7.; 1 folder 2" (Box 374)
    - European Bank for Reconstruction & Development [332.153.5], 1990-2001; 8.; 2 folders 1" (Box 9)
    - European Organizations, Other [488(20)], 1969 & 1985; 9.; 1 folder 0.5" (Box 375)
    - Inter-American Development Bank [332.153.4], 1960-1990; 10.; 1 folder 1" (Box 9)
    - Organization for Economic Cooperation & Development (OECD) [480], 1960-1998; 11.; 1 folder 4" (Box 374)
    - Marshall Plan [480.1], 1972-1997; 12.; 1 folder 1" (Box 374)
    - International Energy Agency (OECD) [480.7], 1975-2001; 13.; 1 folder 3" (Box 375)
    - Nordic Council [488.7], 1968-1991; 14.; 1 folder 1" (Box 375)
    - Western European Union [482], 1964-2000; 15.; 1 folder 2" (Box 375)
  - EUROPEAN COAL & STEEL COMMUNITY, 5.
    - EUROPEAN COAL & STEEL COMMUNITY General
      - EUROPEAN COAL & STEEL COMMUNITY General [45], 1955-1980; 1.; 1 folder 2" (Box 369)
      - Treaty & Legal Questions, ECSC [451], 1959-2002; 2.; 1 folder 1" (Box 370)
      - High Authority [452], 1958-2000; 3.; 1 folder 0.5" (Box 370)
      - Organization, ECSC [452.1], 1954; 4.; 1 folder 0.5"- 3 documents (Box 370)
      - Budget & Financial Questions. ECSC [452.11], 1954-2001; 5.; 1 folder 5" (Box 370)
      - Personnel Regulations ECSC [452.12], 1966-1983; 6.; 1 folder 0.5" (Box 370)
      - Consultative Committee ECSC [452.8], 1958-1992; 7.; 1 folder 5" (Box 370)
      - Council ECSC [453.1], 1965; 8.; 1 folder 0.5" (Box 370)
      - Common Assembly ECSC [453.2], 1954; 9.; 1 folder 1" (Box 370)
      - ECSC, Activities & Situation [456], 2001; 10.; 1 folder 1" (Box 370)
      - ECSC, Weekly Report on the Activities of the High Authority (French) [456.001], 1967; 11.; 1 folder 2" (Box 370)
    - ENERGY
      - ENERGY General [4417], 1964-2002; 1.; 1 folder 3" (Box 353)
      - Energy, ECSC (After 7/1/68 See 4417) [456.2], 1961-1967; 2.; 1 folder 1" (Box 370)
      - Energy, Requirements and Production ECSC (Before 7/1/68 ) [456.21], 1956-1968; 3.; 1 folder 3" (Box 371)
      - Energy Economy (After 7/1/68) [4417.2], 1966-2003; 4.; 1 folder 4" (Box 358)
      - Energy Policy ECSC (Before 7/1/68) [456.22], 1957-1968; 5.; 1 folder 3" (Box 371)
      - Energy Policy (After 7/1/68) [4417.1], 1968-2004; 6.; 7 folders 25" (Box 353)
    - STEEL
      - Steel, Common Market ECSC General (Before 7/1/68) [456.3], 1963-1972; 1.; 1 folder 2" (Box 371)
      - Steel, Common Market ECSC, Specific Measures (Before 7/1/68) [456.32], 1963-1968; 2.; 1 folder 2" (Box 371)
      - Steel, General (After 7/1/68) [443.2], 1963-2003; 3.; 12 folders 40" (Box 188)
      - Steel Scrap, ECSC (Before 7/1/68) [456.322], 1957-1968; 4.; 1 folder 1" (Box 371)
      - Steel scrap (After 7/1/68) [443.221], 1969-1996; 5.; 1 folder 1" (Box 192)
      - Iron Ore, ECSC (Before 7/1/68) [456.323], 1957-1967; 6.; 1 folder 0.5" (Box 371)
      - Iron Ore (After 7/1/68) [443.222], 1969-1985; 7.; 1 folder 1" (Box 192)
      - Steel, General Objectives ECSC (Before 7/1/68) [456.61], 1959-1967; 8.; 1 folder 1" (Box 372)
      - Steel, General Objectives (After 7/1/68) [443.21], 1971-1990; 9.; 1 folder 2" (Box 191)
    - COAL
      - Coal, Common Market ECSC General [456.3], 1963-1972; 1.; 1 folder 2" (Box 371)
      - Coal, Common Market ECSC, Specific Measures (Before 7/1/68) [456.31], 1960-1968; 2.; 1 folder 2" (Box 371)
      - Coal (After 7/1/68) [4417.3], 1953-2003; 3.; 4 folders 16" (Box 359)
    - COMPETITION
      - Competition, ECSC (Before 7/1/68) [456.4], 1958-1967; 1.; 1 folder 1" (Box 372)
      - Steel, Antitrust (After 7/1/68) [444.122], 1968-2001; 2.; 1 folder 2" (Box 201)
    - TRANSPORT
      - Transport, Special Provisions of the ECSC Treaty [447.24], 1954-2001; 1.; 1 folder 1" (Box 279)
      - ECSC, Long Term Development [456.6] (folder missing), 2.; 1 folder (Box 372)
    - INVESTMENT
      - Investment, ECSC (Before 7/1/68) [456.62], 1966 and 1968; 1.; 1 folder 0.5" (Box 372)
      - Investment – ECSC programs (After 7/1/68) [4418.2], 1968-2003; 2.; 1 folder 2" (Box 364)
    - RESEARCH
      - Research Programs, ECSC [456.63], 1958-2003; 1.; 3 folders 14" (Box 372)
    - SOCIAL POLICY
      - Social Policy, ECSC (Before 7/1/68) [456.7], 1952-1968; 1.; 1 folder 1" (Box 373)
      - Social Affairs, General (After 7/1/68) [445], 1960-2003; 2.; 6 folders 19" (Box 208)
      - Employment [445.21], 1967-2003; 3.; 6 folders 35" (Box 210)
      - Housing (After 7/1/68) [445.52], 1964-2003; 4.; 1 folder 2" (Box 222)
      - Housing, ECSC (Before 7/1/68) [456.722], 1956-1968; 5.; 1 folder 1" (Box 373)
      - Industrial Safety Health & Medicine (Before 7/1/68) [456.723], 1959-1967; 6.; 1 folder 1" (Box 373)
      - Labor Relations & Working Conditions (After 7/1/68) [445.3], 1970-2002; 7.; 1 folder 2" (Box 217)
      - Living & Working Conditions, ECSC General (Closed as of 7/1/68) [456.72], 1958; 8.; 1 folder 0.5" (Box 373)
      - Manpower (After 7/1/68) [445.2], 1960-2003; 9.; 2 folders 6" (Box 212)
      - Manpower, ECSC (Before 7/1/68) [456.71], 1955 and 1966; 10.; 1 folder 0.5" (Box 373)
      - Mines Safety Commission (After 7/1/68) [445.84], 1969-2003; 11.; 1 folder 1" (Box 228)
      - Readaptation, ECSC (Before 7/1/68) [456.713], 1956-1967; 12.; 1 folder 1" (Box 373)
      - Readaptation, Reemployment General (After 7/1/68) [445.01], 1968-1999; 13.; 1 folder 1" (Box 211)
      - Reconversion & Redevelopment. ECSC (Before 7/1/68) [456.714], 1966 and 1968; 14.; 1 folder 0.5" (Box 373)
      - Reconversion & Regional Policy, Social Aspects (After 7/1/68) [445.012], 1967-2001; 15.; 1 folder 1" (Box 211)
      - Salaries & Income (After 7/1/68) [445.32], 1960-1999; 16.; 1 folder 2" (Box 219)
      - Salaries, ECSC (Before 7/1/68) [456.721], 1956-1964; 17.; 1 folder 1" (Box 373)
      - Social Security (After 7/1/68) [445.4], 1960-2003; 18.; 2 folder 11" (Box 220)
      - Social Security, ECSC (Before 7/1/68 ) [456.721], 1956-1964; 19.; 1 folder 1" (Box 373)
      - Vocational Training (After 7/1/68) [445.1], 1961-2003; 20.; 3 folder 10" (Box 211)
      - Vocational Training, ECSC (Before 7/1/68) [456.712], 1962 and 1967; 21.; 1 folder 0.5" (Box 373)
      - Working Conditions and Safety Problems in the Coal and Steel Sector (After 7/1/68) [445.83], 1969-1997; 22.; 1 folder 1" (Box 228)
      - Working Conditions, ECSC (Before 7/1/68 ) [456.721], 1956-1964; 23.; 1 folder 1" (Box 373)
      - ECSC, Effects on Member & Non-Member Countries [459] (folder missing), 24.; 1 folder (Box 373)
  - EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES AND EEC, 6.
    - EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES General
      - EUROPEAN COMMUNITIES General [42], 1974-1987; 1.; 1 folder 5" (Box 47)
      - Activities EEC - EC General [44 PART 2], 1961-1987; 2.; 1 folder 3" (Box 94)
      - Activities, European Communities [44 PART 3], 1968-2003; 3.; 1 folder (Box 94)
      - Aid in Emergencies - Natural Disasters [361.9], 1966-2003; 4.; 3 folders 10" (Box 24)
      - Awards Distinctions, European Integration [420 B], 1967-2004; 5.; 1 folder 1 (Box 47)
      - Chronologies [930.24], 1970-2000; 6.; 1 folder 1" (Box 409)
      - Civil Protection [361.91], 1990-2003; 7.; 1 folder 1" (Box 25)
      - Competitions, European Integration [420 A], 1961-2001; 8.; 1 folder 1" (Box 47)
      - Decision-making - Institutional Relationships & Development [43.02], 1959-2003; 9.; 3 folders 14" (Box 71)
      - European (Community) Schools [429.4], 1957-2001; 10.; 2 folders 0.5" (Box 70)
      - European Foundation, The [420.44], 1977-1987; 11.; 2 folders 7" (Box 54)
      - European Integration General [420], 1971-2004; 12.; 1 folder 3" (Box 47)
      - European University [429.3], 1959-1992; 13.; 1 folder 2" (Box 70)
      - Flags Standards [929.9], 1973-2003; 14.; 1 folder 1" (Box 409)
      - Freedom of Information Transparency [44.03], 1992-2003; 15.; 1 folder 3" (Box 95)
      - Fusion of the Executives; Fusion of the Communities [429.2], 1960-1982; 16.; 1 folder 2" (Box 70)
      - Headquarters, EU [429.1], 1959-2003; 17.; 1 folder 3" (Box 69)
      - Maps [912], 1966-2003; 18.; 1 folder 6" (Box 409)
      - Official Languages [342.725], 1958-2003; 19.; 1 folder 5" (Box 22)
      - Personnel European Civil Service [432.12], 1960-2003; 20.; 3 folders 6" (Box 83)
      - Personnel vacancy notices and competitions [432.121], 1974-2003; 21.; 1 folder 3" (Box 84)
      - Personnel Staff Regulations (Including remunerations) [432.122], 1968-2003; 22.; 2 folders 8" (Box 84)
      - Political Integration European [420.4], 1961-1996; 23.; 4 folders 17" (Box 51)
      - Public Opinion [32.019.5], 1964-2003; 24.; 4 folders 11" (Box 6)
      - Sports [796], 1981-2003; 25.; 1 folder 2" (Box 409)
      - Summit Meetings European Integration [420 C], 1967-2004; 26.; 2 folders 3" (Box 48, Box 49, Box 50)
      - List of summits and related documents, 1960-1995; 27.; 16 folders 10" (Box 50)
    - EUROPEAN ECONOMIC COMMUNITY
      - EUROPEAN ECONOMIC COMMUNITY [43], 1957-1985; 1.; 1 folder 2" (Box 71)
      - Activities EEC General [44 PART 1], 1956-1964; 2.; 1 folder 4" (Box 93)
      - Activities EEC General [44 PART 2], 1961-1987; 3.; 1 folder 3" (Box 94)
      - Protocol on the Privileges & Immunities of the EEC [43.01], 1963-1998; 4.; 1 folder 1" (Box 71)
      - EEC Timetable for Treaty Implementation [44.01], 1960-2003; 5.; 1 folder 8" (Box 94)
      - 1965/1966 Crisis [44.02], 1965-1999; 6.; 2 folders 4" (Box 94)
  - EUROPEAN MOVEMENTS & PUBLIC INTEREST GROUPS, 7.
    - EUROPEAN MOVEMENTS
      - European Movement [420.7], 1968-1988; 1.; 1 folder 1" (Box 55)
      - European Movements [420.8], 1969-1983; 2.; 1 folder 0.5" (Box 55)
      - Action Committee for the US of Europe [420.81], 1959-1985; 3.; 1 folder 3" (Box 55)
      - European Federalist Movement [420.82], 1967-1986; 4.; 1 folder 0.5" (Box 55)
      - Centre International de Formation Europeenne [420.83], 1960-1977; 5.; 1 folder 2" (Box 55)
    - PUBLIC INTEREST GROUPS
      - Pressure Groups [301.188], 1968-2002; 1.; 1 folder 2" (Box 3)
      - Farm Organizations, European [301.188: 63(20)], 1970-2003; 2.; 1 folder 2" (Box 4)
      - European Trade Union Institute [331.881: 061], 1977-1987; 3.; 1 folder 1" (Box 9)
      - Labor Unions in the Community [331.881(25)], 1958-1999; 4.; 4 folders 12" (Box 8)
      - Industrial Federations [338.7], 1959-1987; 5.; 1 folder 2" (Box 13)
      - UNICE (Union des Industries); Union of Industries of the European Communities [338.71], 1964-1992; 6.; 1 folder 5" (Box 13)
      - Consumers Groups [339.4: 061.2], 1961-2003; 7.; 1 folder 2" (Box 14)
  - IMPACT OF THE COMMON MARKET ON MEMBER STATES, 8.
    - General [449], 1969-1984; 1.; 1 folder 1" (Box 292)
    - Impact of the Common Market on Trade [449 38], 1968-1982; 2.; 1 folder 1" (Box 292)
    - Austria and the Common Market [449(44)], 1995-2001; 3.; 1 folder 1" (Box 293)
    - Belgium and the Common Market [449(45)], 1970-2001; 4.; 1 folder 2" (Box 293)
    - Denmark and the Common Market [449(66)], 1976-2003; 5.; 1 folder 2" (Box 296)
    - Finland and the Common Market [449(48)], 1994-2002; 6.; 1 folder 1" (Box 293)
    - France and the Common Market [449(49)], 1960-2002; 7.; 1 folder 4" (Box 293)
    - Germany and the Common Market [449(42)], 1970-2001; 8.; 1 folder 3" (Box 292)
    - Greece and the Common Market [449(53)], 1980-2003; 9.; 2 folders 6" (Box 295)
    - Ireland and the Common Market [449(55)], 1970-2002; 10.; 1 folder 4" (Box 295)
    - Italy and the Common Market [449(57)], 1976-2002; 11.; 1 folder 2" (Box 295)
    - Luxembourg and the Common Market [449(58)], 1970-2001; 12.; 1 folder 1" (Box 295)
    - Netherlands and the Common Market [449(60)], 1970-2002; 13.; 1 folder 1" (Box 296)
    - Portugal and the Common Market [449(62)], 1985-2003; 14.; 1 folder 2" (Box 296)
    - Spain and the Common Market [449(47)], 1981-2002; 15.; 1 folder 1" (Box 293)
    - Sweden and the Common Market [449(68)], 1995-2003; 16.; 1 folder 1" (Box 296)
    - United Kingdom and the Common Market [449(51)], 1970-1997; 17.; 4 folders 17" (Box 293, Box 294)
  - INSTITUTIONS, SPECIALIZED AGENCIES & SERVICES, 9.
    - AGENCY FOR HEALTH AND SAFETY AT WORK
      - Agency for Health & Safety at Work [445.821], 1994-2003; 1.; 1 folder 1" (Box 228)
    - COMMISSION
      - Commission of the European Communities [432], 1963-1998; 1.; 6 folders 25" (Box 74, Box 75)
      - Personnel European Civil Service [432.12], 1960-2003; 2.; 3 folders 6" (Box 83)
      - Personnel Vacancy Notices & Competitions [432.121], 1974-2003; 3.; 1 folder 3" (Box 84)
      - Staff Regulations (Including remunerations) [432.122], 1968-2003; 4.; 2 folders 8" (Box 84)
      - Remunerations (Commission Members etc.) [432.123], 1962-1995; 5.; 1 folder 1" (Box 84)
      - Employee Protests & Strikes [432.124], 1963-2001; 6.; 1 folder 2" (Box 84)
      - Internship Program [432.125], 1966-1986; 7.; 1 folder 2" (Box 85)
    - COMMUNITY ARCHIVES
      - Community Archives [427.3], 1981-2003; 1.; 1 folder 1" (Box 69)